<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spencer Chang | creative technologist, story crafter, optimist on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/</link><description>Recent content in Spencer Chang | creative technologist, story crafter, optimist on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>boundless shapeshifters</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</guid><description>54 Views by Tsherin Sherpa
- spencer chang
const poem = ` * Texts * Melodies * clear notes * clear notes, interdependent chords * clear notes, interdependent chords, harmonic tones * for * words * communes of * letters * curving letters * curving, elegant letters * curving, elegant, giving letters * are * boundless shapeshifters, * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes, vibrant dancers), * zealous freedom fighters, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, harbingers of divinity * sacred * sacred (laden with gravitas) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers, imparts visceral feeling) * holders of space * holders of space and keepers of time * holders of space and keepers of time and protectors of life`; const node = createTelescopicTextFromBulletedList(poem); const container = document.</description></item><item><title>beautiful internet</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/beautiful-internet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/beautiful-internet/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mutualistic Flourishing: 2021 to 2022</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</guid><description>Taken on 08.31.2021 Taken on 09.03.2021 Taken on 09.10.2021 In Alaska, life flourishes both on land and in the sea because of mutualistic relationships (lichen + fungi + barnacles) from my photos. This post is a space for my annual reflection, where I look back at the theme I chose last year and set an intention for a theme for the new year.</description></item><item><title>creations are intimacy portals</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/creations-are-intimacy-portals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/creations-are-intimacy-portals/</guid><description>gravity portals are cool and what I imagine these as.
The beginning of the end but the start of something new&amp;hellip;
Wow, this is the 100th mini-essay, the final of the initial intent I started out with. To be honest, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure I would make it this far, and there were definitely moments of berating myself for committing myself publicly to this experiment. I got the seed of this idea from writing a little retro for my 24th birthday, reflecting on my 2021 theme of gambling and what direction I want to take my life and where I draw energy from.</description></item><item><title>beginnings</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beginnings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beginnings/</guid><description>Beginnings are always a mixed bag of feelings. Beginnings are a start, but also an end. A start to a new journey to mark the end of another journey, whether it be the conclusion of a foregone chapter or merely the end of the absence of this new journey. Beginnings can engender dread, anxiety, or excitement: the breath before the exam clock starts ticking, the overthrow of land&amp;rsquo;s dynasty by gravity as one takes the leap, the hum of energy crescendoing to a peak to jumpstart a night to remember.</description></item><item><title>quiet confidence</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/quiet-confidence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/quiet-confidence/</guid><description>I watched this video today after showing up on my Youtube feed and started thinking about how to exude confidence with every ounce of your being. To me, confidence has always felt like a foreign attribute and skill that I need to actively work on. I naturally caveat and hurry through and self-deprecate to serve an artificial to avoid imposing and be looked upon favorable as &amp;ldquo;what a humble guy.&amp;rdquo; It means I&amp;rsquo;ve had to learn to force myself to be confident, even aiming to be arrogant or selfish in order to actually stand up for myself and assert my ground.</description></item><item><title>glorious purpose</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/glorious-purpose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/glorious-purpose/</guid><description>I just finished watching Loki, one of the latest MCU television shows spearheaded by Disney. Some very light spoilers below, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great watch that pulled me into a compelling world and a story that hits on a lot of pressing philosophical problems we face.
A specific scene that stuck with me is when Classic Loki yells out &amp;ldquo;Glorious purpose!&amp;rdquo; as he fights a big boss to help his newfound friends.</description></item><item><title>reclaiming time</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/reclaiming-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/reclaiming-time/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about the concept of time lately, prodded by Jacky&amp;rsquo;s recent thoughts, and have been exploring how we can reclaim our perception and experience of time rather than feeling controlled by it.
In Aaron Lewis' great article about time, he talks about the strange &amp;ldquo;zombie metaphors&amp;rdquo; we use to refer to time and explores the phenomenon of calendar apps intending to give us control but actually making us feel over-booked.</description></item><item><title>ephemeral permanence: an exploration of the future of digital data</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</guid><description>I was talking to Sahil today about low pressure contexts, and we stumbled across an interesting point around how the ephemeral nature of things makes it feel low pressure and safe, but we also want to be able to leverage our technology for storing and retrieving data about every conversation we&amp;rsquo;ve had. How might we get the best of both: the safety of ephemeral thoughts and conversations and moments and the convenience of permanent records and written transcripts and preserved memories?</description></item><item><title>energy liquidity</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/energy-liquidity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/energy-liquidity/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been realizing the over the past couple weeks that not everyone is a maker. It&amp;rsquo;s easy for me to forget because it&amp;rsquo;s the persona I identify most strongly with (see my &amp;ldquo;creative personality type&amp;rdquo; of an artist). I confront the truth again every time I hear what others spend their free time on and contrast this with what my natural desire is to do with my free time. I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about people&amp;rsquo;s relationship to time, and now, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about how people fill that time very differently that point to their priorities and natural dispositions.</description></item><item><title>dance</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dance/</guid><description>Last weekend I had a big milestone. I danced in a performance for this dance workshop I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with for the past 2.5 months, around 8 practices leading up to a performance.
behind the scenes
I tried out dance when I first moved out to San Francisco ~2.5 years ago, and from the start, it has puzzled and intrigued me. Puzzled because it&amp;rsquo;s so ground in instinct and emotion and action, whereas my default is to think and logic my way through things.</description></item><item><title>data stockholm syndrome</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year when holiday songs invade every gap of your awareness, overly ambitious resolutions are made, far too much home food is consumed, and, of course, you and your friends size each other up with your Spotify Wrapped. Our capitalist ideals have already dug themselves deep into the roots of our holiday traditions, in the compulsive gift giving and millions of click-bait Christmas gift listicles that collectively surface for a month and then fade away into the nethers of the Internet.</description></item><item><title>amulets</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/amulets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/amulets/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with Amulets, Robin Sloan&amp;rsquo;s1 NFT project, recently. The basic idea of the project is that anyone can find &amp;ldquo;amulets&amp;rdquo; and then optionally choose to mint them (with an additional operation required to make it &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; and a unenforceable requirement that a link to a carbon offset is also provided). These amulets are &amp;ldquo;poems&amp;rdquo; that satisfy a specific constraint, that they are under 64 bytes and the SHA-256 hex hash of the poem has four or more 8s in a row.</description></item><item><title>future of tools</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/future-of-tools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/future-of-tools/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging in deeper to the web3 world lately, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a fascinating rabbit hole. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me that the web3 space and the tools for thoughts space both share so much in terms of the underlying principles of how technology should be (interoperable, malleable, composable, and more)1, yet there is almost no overlap in the Venn diagram between the two worlds in terms of the people involved.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Magic</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</guid><description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it mindboggling that we created machines that can fly and swim?
In October, I responded to Reboot&amp;rsquo;s manifesto, “Take Back the Future.”, which calls upon technologists to pursue and leverage their unique agency in shaping technology, which has an outsized impact on the future of our livelihoods, to advocate for the people who have less agency and push for a brighter, more equal future. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet from my response:</description></item><item><title>living to provoke</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</guid><description>The other day, under the cover of dim lights embedded in elegant wooden fixtures, we took impassioned guesses at each other&amp;rsquo;s MBTI&amp;rsquo;s. Personality types are an interesting way we use to pretend to be in control of the world and knowing of the world&amp;rsquo;s secrets. We bucket each other into divisions of 16 and 9 and 25 and 12, assigning occupations and strengths, disposition and spirit animals. We tend to like hard divides because they give us the illusion of truth.</description></item><item><title>provocateur</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/provocateur/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/provocateur/</guid><description/></item><item><title>two toned</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/two-toned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/two-toned/</guid><description>Dissonance,
uninhibited heights
cooled by night
Whispers
urgently pressed
to reconcile minds
Outbursts
Melodic giggles
chasing timeless moments
Silences
Tension dripping
Pillows smothered down
Two-toned
Tense light
tale of life.
This is the 88th installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces. Check out the rationale and the full list here.</description></item><item><title>life suppressants</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/life-suppressants/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/life-suppressants/</guid><description>Last night was a classic tale of drinking too much and regretting the state of my body the next morning. My relationship to substances has changed over the past year to honing in on how it’ll allow me live more fully and refusing to give in to any social pressures if it’ll compromise my ability to enjoy and experience every moment. With any substance, dosage is one of the most important factors to your end experience.</description></item><item><title>scope of normality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/scope-of-normality/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/scope-of-normality/</guid><description>Today history took a significant step forward with the craziness around constitution DAO bidding on a copy of the constitution at Sotheby&amp;rsquo;s. They didn&amp;rsquo;t end up winning (a classic American tale of a larger community losing to one rich person), but they stretched the limits of what was believed to be possible, and that makes me think despite the possible ~$3 million USD that was and will be burned in gas to send donations (and now receive the refunds of those donations), it will have all been worth it to show the world what communal action can do.</description></item><item><title>photography origin</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/photography-origin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/photography-origin/</guid><description>Today, I was finally getting around to wrapping up some of the editing on photos from my Alaska trip in September, and I wanted to reflect on and share my origin story for getting involved with photography.
My dad used to always carry around a handheld camcorder and a pocket-sized silver digital Canon. Any special occasion or family trip was accompanied by these portable, digital eyes. I constantly badgered my dad to let me use the small Canon.</description></item><item><title>financialization</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/financialization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/financialization/</guid><description>One of my main hesitations and uncertainties about the future that crypto imagines is the fact that the fundamental building block has a market-based monetary value. This offers a lot of niceities, advocates would argue, like an &amp;ldquo;efficient&amp;rdquo; market and a real stake that users have to offer to show their commitment. However, because the fundamental unit is, despite all the framing as a commodity, a financial instrument that is tradeable and fluctuates in value, we see all the dynamics baggage that these instruments carry with them.</description></item><item><title>allure of ephemerality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/allure-of-ephemerality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/allure-of-ephemerality/</guid><description>I bought my first NFT yesterday. It was from an art collection called Coquina by the artist Jacob Gold. I&amp;rsquo;m generally still hesitant towards the whole NFT space because I think there is a lot of hype that is purely driven by the desire to get rich quick, but the artblocks project around generative NFT art feels very close to the original spirit of NFTs, owning a piece of digital art that supports the artist (and a good cause with 25% of this piece&amp;rsquo;s proceeds going to charity).</description></item><item><title>fear perspectives</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fear-perspectives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fear-perspectives/</guid><description>I came across this tweet from visa, one of my favorite twitter micro celebrities, asking about riffs on fear. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written a lot about fear before, in a poem about conviction and an essay about just doing it, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fail to come up over and over in my daily life. Fear is just so crucial to doing what you want to do. It&amp;rsquo;s the foundational mental blocker underlying all of our doubt and anxiety.</description></item><item><title>facing difficulty</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/facing-difficulty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/facing-difficulty/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in LA right now for Head in the Clouds, one of the first music festivals where I actually am a big fan of a lot of the artists who are performing. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a coffee shop right now in Pasadena, nursing an espresso tonic with slices of dehydrated citrus. The space is bright and airy, featuring an exhibit showcasing the people and stories behind the homeless. On one wall hangs a couple posters, piercing questions set on white font against a black background.</description></item><item><title>conviction</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/conviction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/conviction/</guid><description>Trust yourself when the weather turns.
Press forward even as cloudy omens loom.
Have conviction especially as the arrows eclipse the sky.
When Danger approaches,
Wrap yourself in Conviction to
Ward away the evil.
Impish whispers urge quitting.
Steel your heart with your cowardice—
Fear: perfect for hardening resolve.
This is the 80th installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>vandalism</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/vandalism/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/vandalism/</guid><description>Every kind of creation that is heavily drawn from previous inspirations is &amp;ldquo;vandalism&amp;rdquo; as Denis Villeneuve says. Adaptions, translations, exact replicas are all forms of imitation with varying degrees of change. They all bridge a gap: adaptions connect media, translations connect languages, and replicas connect availability. There&amp;rsquo;s a distinction between adaptions and translations compared to replicas. The former two are intensely difficult creative endeavors in their own right. As they say, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to create a new thing than add to something that exists, and these two art forms require preserving an original voice and intent while also learning when to break the rules to help the source convey the proper messaging in the new environment.</description></item><item><title>impatience</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/impatience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/impatience/</guid><description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to identify why I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling this undercurrent of unease and anxiety the past several months. It&amp;rsquo;s been harder for me to live in the moment and feel relaxed and fully absorbed by whatever I&amp;rsquo;m working on. I feel the draw of consumption as a distraction and method of coping. I&amp;rsquo;m discovering that these feelings can be attributed in a large part to impatience.
I was talking to Ameesh the other day about how at any given moment in a person&amp;rsquo;s life, they are either trying to stay the same, content with how things are going, or are actively trying to change.</description></item><item><title>leverage</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/leverage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/leverage/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been realizing more and more lately how important it is to pay attention to the leverage of actions that you chosoe to spend time on. As I&amp;rsquo;m finding that I have more ideas to explore and initiatives to push forward and visions to realize than I have time, I&amp;rsquo;m figuring out how to prioritize the tasks that maximize the impact to time/effort input ratio.
A big step forward was becoming comfortable with handing projects off and trusting others to take them on.</description></item><item><title>urgency</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/urgency/</guid><description>publishing an ode to urgency from earlier this year:
I write with a sense of urgency now. I write as if my time is limited as if the words I write might disappear at any moment, as if the ideas that shoot across my mind, burning like a meteor entering the atmosphere, have a limited window for capturing before they are lost forever to the ether. I write with a hunger because every second that goes by is another second where insight could inspire a spawn of branches, where expression could embody the essence of a lost feeling, where impact could be the difference between one second living life the fullest and one second living life disappointed.</description></item><item><title>luca</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/luca/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/luca/</guid><description>Wow! #75 means I&amp;rsquo;m 3/4 of the way through this experiment which is crazy to me! I honestly was doubting I&amp;rsquo;d make it this far when I got in about 30-40 because that in itself felt absurd to me. Now, it almost feels like double nature to try to flesh out an idea from a bullet into a whole mini-essay. Quantity hopefully is begetting quality.
Back from the tangent, today&amp;rsquo;s essay is about the Disney + Pixar movie Luca.</description></item><item><title>bad vibes</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/bad-vibes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/bad-vibes/</guid><description>some notes on a realization on bad vibes today and how the opposite is like infinite energy:
seamless and fun collaboration can fuel you forever. my mantra is building cool shit with amazing people. that&amp;rsquo;s the dream
you can be a nice guy while not understanding the vibes some people are used to things going a certain way so they never encounter bad vibes because it&amp;rsquo;s a foreign concept to them (related piece on acclimating to power).</description></item><item><title>pitter patter</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitter-patter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitter-patter/</guid><description>a couple poems on this rainy SF day.
pitter patter pitter patter
the droplets race
pitter patter
the ground laced
pitter patter
the humans hide
pitter patter
as the oceans stride
nothing to see tingling fingers,
pinching innards
disconnect feelings
and entangle urges
trying to run
begets walking;
trying to sing
begets croaking
willing to be
leaves nothing to see.
This is the 73rd installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>soothing fire: a raging fire that cools</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/soothing-fire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/soothing-fire/</guid><description>I met up with jonah today for dinner since he was visiting the city, and we atlked about what we&amp;rsquo;ve been spending time on and the projects we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Jonah&amp;rsquo;s been spending time working at Bubble as well as deeply exploring the crypto space: investing, developing, and now learning how to audit. One thing I really admire about him is that he goes all in on things. You can tell almost off the bat that there&amp;rsquo;s this inner fire burning in him that compels him to act and contribute and push forward for the things that he cares about.</description></item><item><title>ablaze heart</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ablaze-heart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ablaze-heart/</guid><description>Found some inspiring poetry lately so will be forcing myself to do more in the next couple weeks :)
&amp;ldquo;One&amp;rsquo;s true character shows
when the storm comes knocking,
when they&amp;rsquo;re pressed to a wall,
or caught by a trap.
When plans fall through
and dangers come to rest,
the act falls away,
the heart&amp;rsquo;s all that&amp;rsquo;s left.
We long for heroes
in our life of normals.
We yearn for the extraordinary</description></item><item><title>taking what you want</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/taking-what-you-want/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/taking-what-you-want/</guid><description>I have a critical flaw (or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a strength). Despite the influence of substances, there&amp;rsquo;s a certain level of freewheeling behavior that I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to inhabit. It feels foreign, and I guess it is because I&amp;rsquo;ve never acted like that before.
In middle school, the dad of one of my basketball teammates promised me ice cream if i was able to get a foul in the last game of the season.</description></item><item><title>power acclimation</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/power-acclimation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/power-acclimation/</guid><description>I think people naturally acclimate to the mental state they put themselves in over and over and the environment they find themselves acting in day-to-day. It seeps in and takes over our default behavior without us realizing it. If you&amp;rsquo;re used to acquiescing in the face of conflict or running in the face of danger, you&amp;rsquo;re probably a push over. If you protect yourself from pain by pushing away all emotions, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably internalized that it&amp;rsquo;s better to feel nothing than to experience something bad.</description></item><item><title>manifesting</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/manifesting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/manifesting/</guid><description>trying on beliefs is a way to experiment with a different identity. I got this from the hot single nyc advice column for trying on the belief that you being with someone will be complementary. This is like what I was thinking with my thought experiments around turning around my hesitation towards action or anxiety around new situations. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been experiencing the same thing with my earrings—a bit of acting more confident and physically attractive than I felt like I was before?</description></item><item><title>fast feedback loops and perils of convention</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fast-feedback-loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fast-feedback-loops/</guid><description>I had today off too, so I spent the day eating burritos and making some updates to my personal website. I launched my fits stream the other day and started sharing it publicly while making some usability and performance improvements that this new project exposed. Few improvements included adding a permalink + a quick way to copy that link to clipboard since people were referencing their favorites by the #. On the performance side, I added lazy loading for the images and added some responsive image handling so that the content wasn&amp;rsquo;t reflowing every time a new image loaded.</description></item><item><title>unstoppable expression</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/unstoppable-expression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/unstoppable-expression/</guid><description>The few moments in my life where I&amp;rsquo;ve felt unstoppable have been seared into my memory because of how powerful I felt in those times. It&amp;rsquo;s the casual air of quiet confidence that I hangs around superheroes or very dedicated craftspeople. I find that the feeling is heavily tied to a skill or craft that you can feel ownership and proficiency in. The confidence is and limitless energy is a natural consequence of the captivation of your whole essence of being.</description></item><item><title>simple things</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/simple-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/simple-things/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful day in SF, and I&amp;rsquo;m getting the chance to bike around the city again. I really just love this city for the simple things. For the blue skies and the cool breeze and the warm sun. For the red bridge and the evergreen grasses and the turquoise water. For those flaky croissants and also floofy dogs and the pockets of optimistic souls.
It&amp;rsquo;s so beautiful and perfect that it feels like I want to share it with someone.</description></item><item><title>crazy ideas</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/crazy-ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/crazy-ideas/</guid><description>We had Coda&amp;rsquo;s Block Party today, which was a day-long event announcing a bunch of the huge features we&amp;rsquo;re launching soon and hosting many thought leaders to talk about their favorite &amp;ldquo;rituals,&amp;rdquo; repeated processes which keep you or your team productive and healthy. In the final fireside chat between Shishir, our CEO, and Reid Hoffman, a legend of venture investing, Shishir talked again about the initial meeting between them and how this idea seemed crazy at the time.</description></item><item><title>radical migrations</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/radical-migrations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/radical-migrations/</guid><description>When you have something in the world that people are using, making changes becomes hard. With any moderately-sized codebase, a lot of software engineering becomes finding a good compromise with complexity—plugging in your change at the appropriate level of depth for the existing system, rather than making the perfect solution. It&amp;rsquo;s a job of politics: leaving most stakeholders unsatisfied but a little more satisfied than they were before. This can be a tough pill to swallow when you know what it&amp;rsquo;s like to populate a blank canvas with your brain child.</description></item><item><title>re: take back the future - the magic is ours</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</guid><description>In response to take back the future
In high school, I took a computer science class because I liked to play computer games. I never intended for it to become an outlet for expression, a STEM safe haven for my creative urges. I fell for the craft as much as I fell for the people and brands that were the face of it in society.
I&amp;rsquo;m heavily drawn to ideals, so nothing drew me more than the shining G, which had started to become the face of everyone&amp;rsquo;s experience with the internet.</description></item><item><title>intensity</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/intensity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/intensity/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to learn that I really like people who are intense and don&amp;rsquo;t compromise that intensity when it comes to anything that they do. I think intensity gets a bad rep. When I think about intensity, I think about someone rigid who can&amp;rsquo;t relax or adapt to new situations. Somehow I think we&amp;rsquo;ve been conditioned by society to think that these sorts of extreme feelings are bad or undesireable and to limit the amount of time we allow ourselves to feel those.</description></item><item><title>opportunity</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/opportunity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/opportunity/</guid><description>I was talking with Ray today about how the biggest thing I&amp;rsquo;m working on right now is acting on instinct, doing before thinking, trusting myself to get through whatever path I choose in the moment rather than crafting the perfect response to my external stimuli. There&amp;rsquo;s a part of me deep down that fears failure in these situations, and the higher the stakes, the more I feel the pressure. Interpersonal situations are especially effective at generating anxiety and distrust.</description></item><item><title>internet of empty promises</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/internet-of-empty-promises/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/internet-of-empty-promises/</guid><description>Thinking about link rot and ephemerality of the internet and how even things we have control of (our tools) experience this. We run from one shiny tool to the next and often, things don&amp;rsquo;t carry over or if they do import it&amp;rsquo;s not at full fidelity. Software promised us the permanence and stability that paper has never offered, but apps trapped our information in uncompromising and inflexible cages.
This is the 60th installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>app paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/app-paradox/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/app-paradox/</guid><description>Apps are where you interface with people in the digital world. Apps are the place that people are already at, the public places for gathering. To get the connection we&amp;rsquo;ve been blessed with from the internet, you&amp;rsquo;re forced to sign up and play by the rules of various third party app platforms. The good part is that you get to learn about friends and meet new people in these digital spaces.</description></item><item><title>perception</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/perception/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/perception/</guid><description>People&amp;rsquo;s perception of you hinges so much based on your outer appearance. If you wear flamboyant clothes, you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;out there.&amp;rdquo; If you&amp;rsquo;re wearing khakis and hiking boots, you really value comfort, and if you&amp;rsquo;re insistent on thin layers in freezing weather, you value fashion over comfort. These are all common stereotypes that people draw from a single glance, and it can take over your entire impression of a stranger. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this recently because I got my ears pierced yesterday and because of that, I feel like not only my friends but the strangers around me, even more so, are perceiving me differently.</description></item><item><title>arc of the valley</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/arc-of-the-valley/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/arc-of-the-valley/</guid><description>Arc of the valley from Rick, basically the hero&amp;rsquo;s journey but in silicon valley
Bright eyed on the ideals and optimism Disillusionment encountered at the dissonance Deep disillusionment, cynical about everything Matured state of making a difference where you can in your realm of control. Leaving the playground better than you found it The true cynicism comes from dealing with nasty people and artificial problems and finding out that a lot of the promises made around social good are empty.</description></item><item><title>privilege of dreams</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/privilege-of-dreams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/privilege-of-dreams/</guid><description>From a conversation with a friend:
i&amp;rsquo;m also sensing a strong the system is broken vibes around money and having privilege to follow your dreams.. the guy she&amp;rsquo;s casually seeing wants to be a full-time writer and has the monetary means to make it happen. The dynamic around privilege to chase your dreams and having to abide by capitalism can feel very overwhelming. I feel like a lot of people around my age are wrestling with the question of capitalism and what it makes us want to do.</description></item><item><title>irreplaceable</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/irreplaceable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/irreplaceable/</guid><description>Thinking about the fact that coda wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the same if a coworker didn&amp;rsquo;t join, which implies a level of irreplaceability. Being irreplaceable means your value is infinite in our world of supply and demand, as long as the demand is there for what you provide. But the simple fact of being irreplaceable doesn&amp;rsquo;t always coincide with what is needed in the moment or for the long-term. Being irreplaceable has a wide range of meaning.</description></item><item><title>life is fragile</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/life-is-fragile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/life-is-fragile/</guid><description>Life is fragile is a message from Sex Education (fire tv show btw).
The main message is to live for the day because from the hour you’re born you begin to die. Another flavor of live to minimize regrets. We have such limited time on the planet. Don&amp;rsquo;t waste it on people or things that don&amp;rsquo;t make you happy or don&amp;rsquo;t care about you, and cherish the people and things who do because losing them will be incredibly hard.</description></item><item><title>compliments</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/compliments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/compliments/</guid><description>rising lights shining
bright. reaching out beyond the
high, of second sky
that idea about compliments compliments are free energy i actually wrote about in a previous entry on kindness journals, which is wild because it means this experiment is proving its use by giving me a trail of my mental exploration.
This is the 53rd installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>cafe encounter</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/cafe-encounter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/cafe-encounter/</guid><description>Talked to people at Stable Cafe today.
met betty and anton there and chatted them up a lot started because i gave compliment about the DIY jacket to betty, wild how a simple step can result in such a cool connection and conversation anton is super cool. STEAM education curriculum, spiral for french government and international school. Grew up on french island but is italian and was a robotics engineer.</description></item><item><title>extraction and flower</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/extraction-and-flower/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/extraction-and-flower/</guid><description>at second sky, gave one of my flowers to a random guy who hit on me. Reminded by how our smallest acts can make the biggest difference.
i&amp;rsquo;m doing &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; things with friends but a lot of the time it&amp;rsquo;s not actually in the moment fulfilling for me? like I only need these really stereotypically &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; things in small dosages depending on my current mood. For example, I&amp;rsquo;m about to go to porter robinson&amp;rsquo;s second sky music festival, but I actually want to stay in and read about techno-optimism and exploring the relationship between software and people.</description></item><item><title>formulation</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/formulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/formulation/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been really loving George Saunders recently, and I ran into this interview with him and now love him even more because of his perspective:
I don’t know that it [the ending] was the right one. But I think it was the most interesting one. That’s a funny thing about writing stories. We have that illusion that we are “deciding” what to make a character do, in order to “convey our message” or something like that.</description></item><item><title>now's focus</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/nows-focus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/nows-focus/</guid><description>thinking for 100posts that I stop sending everyone an email all the time just send them weekly updates to be less? Good opportunity for me to summarize how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling too and review my writing. start this week?
discovered dk today who did a public journaling thing with Road to Ramen to document his journey to get enough money from the tools he made that he could survive on ramen. This is sort of what I was aiming at with 100posts, but it keeps ending up feeling like more pressure since I&amp;rsquo;m notifying everyone on my list.</description></item><item><title>singular purpose</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/singular-purpose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/singular-purpose/</guid><description>when&amp;rsquo;s the last time I pursued something with singular purpose that wasn&amp;rsquo;t my career? You know those people who really know what they want and they go after it with everything they got and then they seize it and manifest it. I want to manifest the life that I want. manifest is a good theme for next year. What would I choose to pursue with a singular purpose right now? Is it being a good writer?</description></item><item><title>fear</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fear/</guid><description/></item><item><title>pitiful rage</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitiful-rage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitiful-rage/</guid><description/></item><item><title>re-solved problems</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/re-solved-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/re-solved-problems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Liminal Illusions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/liminal-illusions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/liminal-illusions/</guid><description>This is a collage of several journals (composed at various levels of drunkenness) over the past weekend in Vegas, and my post-trip reflections from immersing myself in that environment.
Liminality is defined as the quality of transition between one destination and the next. It’s a state of being that feels unnatural because it’s meant to be temporary. Liminal states and places are defined only by their beginning and end—they have no meaning in absence of their composite destinations.</description></item><item><title>liminal illusions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/liminal-illusions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/liminal-illusions/</guid><description/></item><item><title>kindness journal</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/kindness-journal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/kindness-journal/</guid><description/></item><item><title>fake money</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fake-money/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fake-money/</guid><description/></item><item><title>decisiveness</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/decisiveness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/decisiveness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>blazing lights</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/blazing-lights/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/blazing-lights/</guid><description/></item><item><title>digital capitalism</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/digital-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/digital-capitalism/</guid><description/></item><item><title>weary faces</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/weary-faces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/weary-faces/</guid><description/></item><item><title>personal panopticon</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/personal-panopticon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/personal-panopticon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>empty mind</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/empty-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/empty-mind/</guid><description/></item><item><title>repetition</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/repetition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/repetition/</guid><description/></item><item><title>denim personality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/denim-personality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/denim-personality/</guid><description/></item><item><title>denim personality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</guid><description>I’ve been getting really into fashion lately. Perhaps my visit to New York was what really kicked it into overdrive for me given the opportunity to get inspiration everywhere you go on the street, but I’ve always been enamored with the idea of fashion and making yourself look good to feel good. As a child, I was bold with my choices. According to my dad who resurfaced an old journal entry recently, I once tried on some shoes in a store and refused to take them off because I was so enamored with them, and my parents ended up having to buy this nice pair of shoes for a 5-year-old (what a difficult child I must have been 😅).</description></item><item><title>the same thing</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-same-thing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-same-thing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>chasing stability</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/chasing-stability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/chasing-stability/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the technology paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-technology-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-technology-paradox/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the technology paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</guid><description>Under 280 in San Francisco during golden hour.
Yesterday, I made the trek down to Palo Alto for Alex&amp;rsquo;s birthday and had a great time in the afternoon barbecuing, laughing, and enjoying the South Bay summer. I was realizing it was the first time in the Bay where I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a large gathering that wasn&amp;rsquo;t predominantly people in the tech industry. Alex is a graduate student in physics at Stanford, so the party was full of PhD candidates and high school friends who&amp;rsquo;ve covered a spread across the different fields.</description></item><item><title>the gaps</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-gaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-gaps/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the gaps</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</guid><description>thumping beats, reverberating ground a ritualized welcome or a dreadful threat to the entrants strangers and substances a perfect match for forgotten nights and regrettable fights the empty spaces of life those gaps in the space between the lived and the unlivable between the vocalized and the omitted water surges from within to fill those that make us ache with the rhythm of that fateful beat, that make us rage with the hot fury of those substances’ burn I reach out for the spaces yet they reach away an infinite chase, head after tail a still, pristine lake above a single drop triggers the climax below These gaps exist to be reached Yes, we live for reaching but oh!</description></item><item><title>uneven time</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/uneven-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/uneven-time/</guid><description/></item><item><title>uneven time</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</guid><description>an art piece representing the fish of lijiang by James W Hedges
I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself catching myself from thinking too quickly recently, the thoughts tumbling over each other and jostling for the room to breathe. Sometimes my mind feels like a bumping nightclub in the rush of the night&amp;mdash;overwhelming sights and sounds fighting for your attention. The game is one of being more attractive, more provocative, more desirable than all the others, and the battleground is our senses.</description></item><item><title>a drop of color</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/a-drop-of-color/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/a-drop-of-color/</guid><description/></item><item><title>home and fake nostalgia</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/home-and-fake-nostalgia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/home-and-fake-nostalgia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>do more, be more</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/do-more-be-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/do-more-be-more/</guid><description/></item><item><title>silent conversations</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/silent-conversations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/silent-conversations/</guid><description/></item><item><title>dauntlessness</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dauntlessness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dauntlessness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>trust</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/trust/</guid><description/></item><item><title>reflection systems</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/reflection-systems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/reflection-systems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>aperture of life</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/aperture-of-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/aperture-of-life/</guid><description/></item><item><title>i can only get smarter by being dumb and other advice to myself</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/i-can-only-get-smarter-by-being-dumb-and-other-advice-to-myself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/i-can-only-get-smarter-by-being-dumb-and-other-advice-to-myself/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the silo culture</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-silo-culture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-silo-culture/</guid><description/></item><item><title>commitment and obligation</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/commitment-and-obligation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/commitment-and-obligation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>commitment and obligation</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/commitment-and-obligation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/commitment-and-obligation/</guid><description>The first time I ran 3 miles was during a typical Houston summer, hot and humid. It was just past one, past the hottest time of day but still above 90, still hot enough to see the light shimmering in the liminal space between the planes where your eyes focused. I started cross country in middle school to follow my brother’s footsteps, and I kept with it because I figured it was a good way to keep myself fit.</description></item><item><title>beauty</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beauty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beauty/</guid><description/></item><item><title>remixing</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/remixing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/remixing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rituals at Scale: How we remixed templates</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>making shit</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/making-shit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/making-shit/</guid><description/></item><item><title>finding texture</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/finding-texture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/finding-texture/</guid><description/></item><item><title>how i found my snow</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/snow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/snow/</guid><description/></item><item><title>slow burn</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/slow-burn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/slow-burn/</guid><description/></item><item><title>realizing an idea</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/realizing-an-idea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/realizing-an-idea/</guid><description/></item><item><title>dampening of curiosity</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dampening-of-curiosity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dampening-of-curiosity/</guid><description/></item><item><title>dancing through life</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dancing-through-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/dancing-through-life/</guid><description/></item><item><title>craft over career</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/craft-over-career/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/craft-over-career/</guid><description/></item><item><title>craft over career</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter.
I came across this tweet today on a life philosophy to follow that really resonated with me.
mads mikkelsen, career coach https://t.co/WftIqaBxfd pic.twitter.com/OIAJZ6mtFm
&amp;mdash; E. Alex Jung (@e_alexjung) April 20, 2021 everything I do is the most important thing I do&amp;hellip;. I will be ambitious with my job and not my career.
The implication of this statement is that whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing now is the most important thing for you, not some stepping stone for a future greatness.</description></item><item><title>zoom fatigue and low pressure contexts</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/low-pressure-contexts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/low-pressure-contexts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>shaping the world</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/shaping-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/shaping-the-world/</guid><description/></item><item><title>why do uncomfortable chairs exist?</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/uncomfortable-chairs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/uncomfortable-chairs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>samishii and nostalgia</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/samishii-and-nostalgia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/samishii-and-nostalgia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the superpower of naming</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-superpower-of-naming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-superpower-of-naming/</guid><description/></item><item><title>vibe tribes and finding psychological oxygen</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/vibe-tribes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/vibe-tribes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the mid twenties</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-mid-twenties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/the-mid-twenties/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the mid-twenties</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter. This was also my 1st installment in my 100 mini-essays experiment.
a colorful storefront I found in Buenos Aires (more at my instagram)
So I turned 24 yesterday and the biggest question on my mind (as it seems to have incepted all of my friends’ minds) is: does 24 count as “mid-twenties”? “Welcome to your mid-twenties” my friends quip.</description></item><item><title>towards 2021</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/towards-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/towards-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gambling on Dreams</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</guid><description>A vibration ripples out from my phone. It’s a message from a classmate asking about my rooming plans for next semester with a not-so-subtle suggestion at a better option. I’m nearing the end of my first year in college, and having been successful at my quest to fit in, I’m tempted to change as little as possible to keep the good things going. The proposal to room with someone new (who I knew from the very intimate experience of recognizing their face across the dining hall every once in a while) was both an opportunity and a risk.</description></item><item><title>diluted stars, islands, civic tech, and 🍜</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/diluted-stars-islands-civic-tech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/newsletter/diluted-stars-islands-civic-tech/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dilution</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</guid><description>Under my watchful eyes, a weight settles over the world. Thick layers of shadows pile on top of one another until all that’s left poking out in the sea of night are tiny fireflies, little torches signaling life. I look out my golden-ratioed window, a precise, technical masterpiece with a reinforced panel of glass acting as a projector for the production playing out beyond. In the distant horizon, the line where the sky meets the world and the galactic bend, glinting ever so inconspicuously, levels with my eyes.</description></item><item><title>Making the World a Better Place: A Valley of Smoke and Mirrors</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/better-world-delusion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/better-world-delusion/</guid><description>a beach along Route 1 covered by the fog (photo credit spencerchang.photography)
To communicate an identity requires some degree of self-delusion. A performer, in order to be convincing, must conceal “the discreditable facts that he has had to learn about the performance; in everyday terms, there will be things he knows, or has known, that he will not be able to tell himself.” ー Trick Mirror: Reflections on Self-Delusion by Jia Tolentino summarizing Erving Goffman In second grade, we did an assignment on our dream jobs.</description></item><item><title>Making the “Right” Decisions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</guid><description>A mother and cub flourishing in the remains of a whaling station in Grytviken&amp;ndash;an example of something &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; becoming wrong. (for more)
Growing up, I strove to do all the “right” things. I was told that doing well in school was good, so I studied, toiled, and recited for good grades. I was told that being polite and obedient was proper, so I sucked up my protests and did what was demanded of me without question.</description></item><item><title>George Floyd</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/george-floyd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/george-floyd/</guid><description>SF George Floyd Protest 06/03 for more see my instagram This week should have felt like another rude awakening for those of us who have rarely had to think about the problems in our criminal justice system and how our country handles protecting our communities.</description></item><item><title>Broken Lines</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</guid><description>a stack of logs on a Napa trip (for more photos)
But in a life of activity, one free from dramatic rupture, where the progress of things is unbroken by catastrophe, where the skin of our thoughts is regularly touched by new impressions, discoveries and influences, our maturation comes to follow a gradient that creates the illusion of a seamless line. With Uncle Hmad, the young man he was at the point of his arrest and the man he has become seemed to exist in parallel, destined never to meet and yet resonating against one another like two discordant musical notes.</description></item><item><title>a twinkle</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</guid><description>A shaft of moonlight pierces the curtain
In my concrete abode, a flare lighting the way out
The ephemeral promise draws me
like a firefly I seek my hopes.
The defeaning chorus of cicadas
consumes me in the darkness.
Out in the fields, the grains cultivated
What was promised eclipses the night
A permanent night light bathes me
as the swarm of stars engulfs me
from the infinite black canvas above</description></item><item><title>Crowdsourced Birthday Recommendations</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/crowdsourced-birthday-recs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/crowdsourced-birthday-recs/</guid><description>I collected anonymous (or not) birthday recommendations and feedback. It was amazing to hear from so many people, both close friends and acquaintances and their inner thoughts. I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to everyone who filled it out!
It all started in a bright hospital room in downtown Houston&amp;hellip;
Ok maybe not that far back, but essentially I got the idea from my friend Kevin Lau who did the same thing for his birthday.</description></item><item><title>The War of Intentions and Beliefs</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</guid><description>What happens when good intentions are lost, everyone wants to be a hero, and the fight against evil spills over into innocents.</description></item><item><title>Decoding your Mind</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/decoding-your-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/decoding-your-mind/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Discovering a New Year</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</guid><description>Exploration—the relinquishing of the old for something new and unknown. Why do we explore? What drives us to leave behind cozy homes, comfortable routines, and familiar lands, foods, and faces to seek out the new and unknown?</description></item><item><title>Opening the Lid on the Workspace Black Box</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/opening-the-lid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/opening-the-lid/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</guid><description>The night was cold and dark. The moon shone brightly, gently singing her graceful hymn. The light didn’t shine very far, however. A thick wall of sinister clouds prevented any escape of the beautiful song below.</description></item><item><title>Sublime Arts</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</guid><description>1:45 am. We had just gotten back from the movies, and I was going through the regular ritual of preparing for my nightly recharge. The room was pitch dark except for the flickering amalgam of multicolored lights dancing across the window: reflections mirroring the revelry of a city alive at night.
As I was finishing my movements in robotic silence, an irregular symphony of beats stirred me from my semi-wakeful, semi-listless state.</description></item><item><title>Rice Fields and Murky Identities</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rice-fields/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rice-fields/</guid><description>Rice fields right outside 宜梧 (YiWu) Junior High School during sunset (taken on my Nikon D3400)
“来吃饭了！(literally, &amp;lsquo;come eat!&amp;rsquo; but interpreted as &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo;s ready!&amp;rsquo; )” rang through the hallways of my house, emanating from the kitchen. This was a daily occurrence, after a long day of school or work, signaling that dinner, which my 奶奶 (grandma) had lovingly prepared, was ready. Growing up in a Chinese American household, I was lucky to have my grandma live with us; this forced me to learn Mandarin from a young age because she couldn’t speak English.</description></item><item><title>From Student to Teacher</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/student-to-teacher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/student-to-teacher/</guid><description>Photo by Mwesigwa Joel on Unsplash
”誰是我們的老師啊？(Who are our teachers?)“
“是我們 (We are)” I blurted.
Shit. We had just finished a whole week of training where we were specifically told to pretend not to know Chinese to encourage our students to speak English. And I had just responded in Chinese to their question. Great, first minute of “teaching” and I already messed up. How am I gonna survive 2 weeks of this?</description></item><item><title>Stupid Scholars, the Power of Hands, and Free Lunches: Riding Through 4 Years of University</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</guid><description>“It’ll be fine,” I reassured myself for what seemed like the millionth time. The mere prospect of a roller coaster ride had reduced me to a broken record. I’ve never been a follower of the camp that derives thrill, much less joy, from artificial fear. Horror movies are a hard no, especially at night, alone in my room, and maybe it’s obvious, but I had never ridden a roller coaster.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Knowledge Access and Retrieval at Airbnb</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/knowledge-graph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/knowledge-graph/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>