<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>beliefs on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/beliefs/</link><description>Recent content in beliefs on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/beliefs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>re: take back the future - the magic is ours</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</guid><description>In response to take back the future
In high school, I took a computer science class because I liked to play computer games. I never intended for it to become an outlet for expression, a STEM safe haven for my creative urges. I fell for the craft as much as I fell for the people and brands that were the face of it in society.
I&amp;rsquo;m heavily drawn to ideals, so nothing drew me more than the shining G, which had started to become the face of everyone&amp;rsquo;s experience with the internet.</description></item><item><title>denim personality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</guid><description>I’ve been getting really into fashion lately. Perhaps my visit to New York was what really kicked it into overdrive for me given the opportunity to get inspiration everywhere you go on the street, but I’ve always been enamored with the idea of fashion and making yourself look good to feel good. As a child, I was bold with my choices. According to my dad who resurfaced an old journal entry recently, I once tried on some shoes in a store and refused to take them off because I was so enamored with them, and my parents ended up having to buy this nice pair of shoes for a 5-year-old (what a difficult child I must have been 😅).</description></item><item><title>the technology paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</guid><description>Under 280 in San Francisco during golden hour.
Yesterday, I made the trek down to Palo Alto for Alex&amp;rsquo;s birthday and had a great time in the afternoon barbecuing, laughing, and enjoying the South Bay summer. I was realizing it was the first time in the Bay where I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a large gathering that wasn&amp;rsquo;t predominantly people in the tech industry. Alex is a graduate student in physics at Stanford, so the party was full of PhD candidates and high school friends who&amp;rsquo;ve covered a spread across the different fields.</description></item><item><title>craft over career</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter.
I came across this tweet today on a life philosophy to follow that really resonated with me.
mads mikkelsen, career coach https://t.co/WftIqaBxfd pic.twitter.com/OIAJZ6mtFm
&amp;mdash; E. Alex Jung (@e_alexjung) April 20, 2021 everything I do is the most important thing I do&amp;hellip;. I will be ambitious with my job and not my career.
The implication of this statement is that whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing now is the most important thing for you, not some stepping stone for a future greatness.</description></item><item><title>the mid-twenties</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter. This was also my 1st installment in my 100 mini-essays experiment.
a colorful storefront I found in Buenos Aires (more at my instagram)
So I turned 24 yesterday and the biggest question on my mind (as it seems to have incepted all of my friends’ minds) is: does 24 count as “mid-twenties”? “Welcome to your mid-twenties” my friends quip.</description></item></channel></rss>