<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/software/</link><description>Recent content in software on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ephemeral permanence: an exploration of the future of digital data</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</guid><description>I was talking to Sahil today about low pressure contexts, and we stumbled across an interesting point around how the ephemeral nature of things makes it feel low pressure and safe, but we also want to be able to leverage our technology for storing and retrieving data about every conversation we&amp;rsquo;ve had. How might we get the best of both: the safety of ephemeral thoughts and conversations and moments and the convenience of permanent records and written transcripts and preserved memories?</description></item><item><title>data stockholm syndrome</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year when holiday songs invade every gap of your awareness, overly ambitious resolutions are made, far too much home food is consumed, and, of course, you and your friends size each other up with your Spotify Wrapped. Our capitalist ideals have already dug themselves deep into the roots of our holiday traditions, in the compulsive gift giving and millions of click-bait Christmas gift listicles that collectively surface for a month and then fade away into the nethers of the Internet.</description></item><item><title>future of tools</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/future-of-tools/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/future-of-tools/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging in deeper to the web3 world lately, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a fascinating rabbit hole. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me that the web3 space and the tools for thoughts space both share so much in terms of the underlying principles of how technology should be (interoperable, malleable, composable, and more)1, yet there is almost no overlap in the Venn diagram between the two worlds in terms of the people involved.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Magic</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</guid><description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it mindboggling that we created machines that can fly and swim?
In October, I responded to Reboot&amp;rsquo;s manifesto, “Take Back the Future.”, which calls upon technologists to pursue and leverage their unique agency in shaping technology, which has an outsized impact on the future of our livelihoods, to advocate for the people who have less agency and push for a brighter, more equal future. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet from my response:</description></item><item><title>fast feedback loops and perils of convention</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fast-feedback-loops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/fast-feedback-loops/</guid><description>I had today off too, so I spent the day eating burritos and making some updates to my personal website. I launched my fits stream the other day and started sharing it publicly while making some usability and performance improvements that this new project exposed. Few improvements included adding a permalink + a quick way to copy that link to clipboard since people were referencing their favorites by the #. On the performance side, I added lazy loading for the images and added some responsive image handling so that the content wasn&amp;rsquo;t reflowing every time a new image loaded.</description></item><item><title>internet of empty promises</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/internet-of-empty-promises/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/internet-of-empty-promises/</guid><description>Thinking about link rot and ephemerality of the internet and how even things we have control of (our tools) experience this. We run from one shiny tool to the next and often, things don&amp;rsquo;t carry over or if they do import it&amp;rsquo;s not at full fidelity. Software promised us the permanence and stability that paper has never offered, but apps trapped our information in uncompromising and inflexible cages.
This is the 60th installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>personal panopticon</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/personal-panopticon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/personal-panopticon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the technology paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</guid><description>Under 280 in San Francisco during golden hour.
Yesterday, I made the trek down to Palo Alto for Alex&amp;rsquo;s birthday and had a great time in the afternoon barbecuing, laughing, and enjoying the South Bay summer. I was realizing it was the first time in the Bay where I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a large gathering that wasn&amp;rsquo;t predominantly people in the tech industry. Alex is a graduate student in physics at Stanford, so the party was full of PhD candidates and high school friends who&amp;rsquo;ve covered a spread across the different fields.</description></item><item><title>Rituals at Scale: How we remixed templates</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>shaping the world</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/shaping-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/shaping-the-world/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>