<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>creative on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/creative/</link><description>Recent content in creative on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/creative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>boundless shapeshifters</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</guid><description>54 Views by Tsherin Sherpa
- spencer chang
const poem = ` * Texts * Melodies * clear notes * clear notes, interdependent chords * clear notes, interdependent chords, harmonic tones * for * words * communes of * letters * curving letters * curving, elegant letters * curving, elegant, giving letters * are * boundless shapeshifters, * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes, vibrant dancers), * zealous freedom fighters, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, harbingers of divinity * sacred * sacred (laden with gravitas) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers, imparts visceral feeling) * holders of space * holders of space and keepers of time * holders of space and keepers of time and protectors of life`; const node = createTelescopicTextFromBulletedList(poem); const container = document.</description></item><item><title>beginnings</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beginnings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/beginnings/</guid><description>Beginnings are always a mixed bag of feelings. Beginnings are a start, but also an end. A start to a new journey to mark the end of another journey, whether it be the conclusion of a foregone chapter or merely the end of the absence of this new journey. Beginnings can engender dread, anxiety, or excitement: the breath before the exam clock starts ticking, the overthrow of land&amp;rsquo;s dynasty by gravity as one takes the leap, the hum of energy crescendoing to a peak to jumpstart a night to remember.</description></item><item><title>photography origin</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/photography-origin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/photography-origin/</guid><description>Today, I was finally getting around to wrapping up some of the editing on photos from my Alaska trip in September, and I wanted to reflect on and share my origin story for getting involved with photography.
My dad used to always carry around a handheld camcorder and a pocket-sized silver digital Canon. Any special occasion or family trip was accompanied by these portable, digital eyes. I constantly badgered my dad to let me use the small Canon.</description></item><item><title>conviction</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/conviction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/conviction/</guid><description>Trust yourself when the weather turns.
Press forward even as cloudy omens loom.
Have conviction especially as the arrows eclipse the sky.
When Danger approaches,
Wrap yourself in Conviction to
Ward away the evil.
Impish whispers urge quitting.
Steel your heart with your cowardice—
Fear: perfect for hardening resolve.
This is the 80th installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>urgency</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/urgency/</guid><description>publishing an ode to urgency from earlier this year:
I write with a sense of urgency now. I write as if my time is limited as if the words I write might disappear at any moment, as if the ideas that shoot across my mind, burning like a meteor entering the atmosphere, have a limited window for capturing before they are lost forever to the ether. I write with a hunger because every second that goes by is another second where insight could inspire a spawn of branches, where expression could embody the essence of a lost feeling, where impact could be the difference between one second living life the fullest and one second living life disappointed.</description></item><item><title>pitter patter</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitter-patter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitter-patter/</guid><description>a couple poems on this rainy SF day.
pitter patter pitter patter
the droplets race
pitter patter
the ground laced
pitter patter
the humans hide
pitter patter
as the oceans stride
nothing to see tingling fingers,
pinching innards
disconnect feelings
and entangle urges
trying to run
begets walking;
trying to sing
begets croaking
willing to be
leaves nothing to see.
This is the 73rd installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>ablaze heart</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ablaze-heart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ablaze-heart/</guid><description>Found some inspiring poetry lately so will be forcing myself to do more in the next couple weeks :)
&amp;ldquo;One&amp;rsquo;s true character shows
when the storm comes knocking,
when they&amp;rsquo;re pressed to a wall,
or caught by a trap.
When plans fall through
and dangers come to rest,
the act falls away,
the heart&amp;rsquo;s all that&amp;rsquo;s left.
We long for heroes
in our life of normals.
We yearn for the extraordinary</description></item><item><title>compliments</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/compliments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/compliments/</guid><description>rising lights shining
bright. reaching out beyond the
high, of second sky
that idea about compliments compliments are free energy i actually wrote about in a previous entry on kindness journals, which is wild because it means this experiment is proving its use by giving me a trail of my mental exploration.
This is the 53rd installment in my experiment of publishing raw, lightly edited mini-essays every day towards achieving 100 public pieces.</description></item><item><title>pitiful rage</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitiful-rage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/pitiful-rage/</guid><description/></item><item><title>weary faces</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/weary-faces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/weary-faces/</guid><description/></item><item><title>the gaps</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</guid><description>thumping beats, reverberating ground a ritualized welcome or a dreadful threat to the entrants strangers and substances a perfect match for forgotten nights and regrettable fights the empty spaces of life those gaps in the space between the lived and the unlivable between the vocalized and the omitted water surges from within to fill those that make us ache with the rhythm of that fateful beat, that make us rage with the hot fury of those substances’ burn I reach out for the spaces yet they reach away an infinite chase, head after tail a still, pristine lake above a single drop triggers the climax below These gaps exist to be reached Yes, we live for reaching but oh!</description></item><item><title>uneven time</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</guid><description>an art piece representing the fish of lijiang by James W Hedges
I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself catching myself from thinking too quickly recently, the thoughts tumbling over each other and jostling for the room to breathe. Sometimes my mind feels like a bumping nightclub in the rush of the night&amp;mdash;overwhelming sights and sounds fighting for your attention. The game is one of being more attractive, more provocative, more desirable than all the others, and the battleground is our senses.</description></item><item><title>Dilution</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</guid><description>Under my watchful eyes, a weight settles over the world. Thick layers of shadows pile on top of one another until all that’s left poking out in the sea of night are tiny fireflies, little torches signaling life. I look out my golden-ratioed window, a precise, technical masterpiece with a reinforced panel of glass acting as a projector for the production playing out beyond. In the distant horizon, the line where the sky meets the world and the galactic bend, glinting ever so inconspicuously, levels with my eyes.</description></item><item><title>a twinkle</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</guid><description>A shaft of moonlight pierces the curtain
In my concrete abode, a flare lighting the way out
The ephemeral promise draws me
like a firefly I seek my hopes.
The defeaning chorus of cicadas
consumes me in the darkness.
Out in the fields, the grains cultivated
What was promised eclipses the night
A permanent night light bathes me
as the swarm of stars engulfs me
from the infinite black canvas above</description></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</guid><description>The night was cold and dark. The moon shone brightly, gently singing her graceful hymn. The light didn’t shine very far, however. A thick wall of sinister clouds prevented any escape of the beautiful song below.</description></item><item><title>Sublime Arts</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</guid><description>1:45 am. We had just gotten back from the movies, and I was going through the regular ritual of preparing for my nightly recharge. The room was pitch dark except for the flickering amalgam of multicolored lights dancing across the window: reflections mirroring the revelry of a city alive at night.
As I was finishing my movements in robotic silence, an irregular symphony of beats stirred me from my semi-wakeful, semi-listless state.</description></item></channel></rss>