<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reflection on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/reflection/</link><description>Recent content in reflection on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>the mid-twenties</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter. This was also my 1st installment in my 100 mini-essays experiment.
a colorful storefront I found in Buenos Aires (more at my instagram)
So I turned 24 yesterday and the biggest question on my mind (as it seems to have incepted all of my friends’ minds) is: does 24 count as “mid-twenties”? “Welcome to your mid-twenties” my friends quip.</description></item><item><title>spiraling in 2024</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/spiraling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/spiraling/</guid><description>spiraling in 2024 Every year, I do an annual reflection where I write a letter to my past self looking back on my theme for the year and setting an intention for a new theme moving forward. Last year, I took on motion as a theme.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been caught in various spirals over the past few months. Questions around my worth, the importance of my work, and the strength of my love for the world.</description></item><item><title>motion, rhythm, gardening cycles</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/motion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/motion/</guid><description>Every year, I do an annual reflection where I write a letter to my past self looking back on my theme for the year and set an intention for a new theme moving forward. Last year, I took on mutualism as a theme.
flourishing in community in 2022 Dear Spencer,
This year you&amp;rsquo;ll feel on top of the world in so many ways: doing things you once doubted even having the right to think about, finding wonder in so many unexpected places, sculpting ever closer towards a dream you have full conviction in.</description></item><item><title>the foil of narcissism</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/narcissism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/narcissism/</guid><description>still of a mirror shot from A Portrait of a Lady on Fire
After significant personal reflection, I think I&amp;rsquo;m ready to become a narcissist. What does that mean? You might be imagining taking a moment to enjoy every time you look in the mirror. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. It also means believing you have a divine right to exert your domain. Like believing that being served the most complicated Starbucks drink on Earth is key to humanity&amp;rsquo;s survival.</description></item><item><title>Mutualistic Flourishing: 2021 to 2022</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</guid><description>Taken on 08.31.2021 Taken on 09.03.2021 Taken on 09.10.2021 In Alaska, life flourishes both on land and in the sea because of mutualistic relationships (lichen + fungi + barnacles) from my photos. This post is a space for my annual reflection, where I look back at the theme I chose last year and set an intention for a theme for the new year.</description></item><item><title>Gambling on Dreams</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</guid><description>A vibration ripples out from my phone. It’s a message from a classmate asking about my rooming plans for next semester with a not-so-subtle suggestion at a better option. I’m nearing the end of my first year in college, and having been successful at my quest to fit in, I’m tempted to change as little as possible to keep the good things going. The proposal to room with someone new (who I knew from the very intimate experience of recognizing their face across the dining hall every once in a while) was both an opportunity and a risk.</description></item><item><title>Discovering a New Year</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</guid><description>Exploration—the relinquishing of the old for something new and unknown. Why do we explore? What drives us to leave behind cozy homes, comfortable routines, and familiar lands, foods, and faces to seek out the new and unknown?</description></item><item><title>Stupid Scholars, the Power of Hands, and Free Lunches: Riding Through 4 Years of University</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</guid><description>“It’ll be fine,” I reassured myself for what seemed like the millionth time. The mere prospect of a roller coaster ride had reduced me to a broken record. I’ve never been a follower of the camp that derives thrill, much less joy, from artificial fear. Horror movies are a hard no, especially at night, alone in my room, and maybe it’s obvious, but I had never ridden a roller coaster.</description></item></channel></rss>