<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>boundless shapeshifters</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/boundless-shapeshifters/</guid><description>54 Views by Tsherin Sherpa
- spencer chang
const poem = ` * Texts * Melodies * clear notes * clear notes, interdependent chords * clear notes, interdependent chords, harmonic tones * for * words * communes of * letters * curving letters * curving, elegant letters * curving, elegant, giving letters * are * boundless shapeshifters, * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes), * boundless shapeshifters (technicolor chameleons, expanding universes, vibrant dancers), * zealous freedom fighters, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, * zealous freedom fighters, champions of liberty, harbingers of divinity * sacred * sacred (laden with gravitas) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers) * sacred (laden with gravitas, revered by followers, imparts visceral feeling) * holders of space * holders of space and keepers of time * holders of space and keepers of time and protectors of life`; const node = createTelescopicTextFromBulletedList(poem); const container = document.</description></item><item><title>Mutualistic Flourishing: 2021 to 2022</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mutualism/</guid><description>Taken on 08.31.2021 Taken on 09.03.2021 Taken on 09.10.2021 In Alaska, life flourishes both on land and in the sea because of mutualistic relationships (lichen + fungi + barnacles) from my photos. This post is a space for my annual reflection, where I look back at the theme I chose last year and set an intention for a theme for the new year.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Magic</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</guid><description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it mindboggling that we created machines that can fly and swim?
In October, I responded to Reboot&amp;rsquo;s manifesto, “Take Back the Future.”, which calls upon technologists to pursue and leverage their unique agency in shaping technology, which has an outsized impact on the future of our livelihoods, to advocate for the people who have less agency and push for a brighter, more equal future. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet from my response:</description></item><item><title>living to provoke</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</guid><description>The other day, under the cover of dim lights embedded in elegant wooden fixtures, we took impassioned guesses at each other&amp;rsquo;s MBTI&amp;rsquo;s. Personality types are an interesting way we use to pretend to be in control of the world and knowing of the world&amp;rsquo;s secrets. We bucket each other into divisions of 16 and 9 and 25 and 12, assigning occupations and strengths, disposition and spirit animals. We tend to like hard divides because they give us the illusion of truth.</description></item><item><title>re: take back the future - the magic is ours</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/take-back-the-future-response/</guid><description>In response to take back the future
In high school, I took a computer science class because I liked to play computer games. I never intended for it to become an outlet for expression, a STEM safe haven for my creative urges. I fell for the craft as much as I fell for the people and brands that were the face of it in society.
I&amp;rsquo;m heavily drawn to ideals, so nothing drew me more than the shining G, which had started to become the face of everyone&amp;rsquo;s experience with the internet.</description></item><item><title>Liminal Illusions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/liminal-illusions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/liminal-illusions/</guid><description>This is a collage of several journals (composed at various levels of drunkenness) over the past weekend in Vegas, and my post-trip reflections from immersing myself in that environment.
Liminality is defined as the quality of transition between one destination and the next. It’s a state of being that feels unnatural because it’s meant to be temporary. Liminal states and places are defined only by their beginning and end—they have no meaning in absence of their composite destinations.</description></item><item><title>denim personality</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/denim-personality/</guid><description>I’ve been getting really into fashion lately. Perhaps my visit to New York was what really kicked it into overdrive for me given the opportunity to get inspiration everywhere you go on the street, but I’ve always been enamored with the idea of fashion and making yourself look good to feel good. As a child, I was bold with my choices. According to my dad who resurfaced an old journal entry recently, I once tried on some shoes in a store and refused to take them off because I was so enamored with them, and my parents ended up having to buy this nice pair of shoes for a 5-year-old (what a difficult child I must have been 😅).</description></item><item><title>the technology paradox</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/technology-paradox/</guid><description>Under 280 in San Francisco during golden hour.
Yesterday, I made the trek down to Palo Alto for Alex&amp;rsquo;s birthday and had a great time in the afternoon barbecuing, laughing, and enjoying the South Bay summer. I was realizing it was the first time in the Bay where I&amp;rsquo;ve attended a large gathering that wasn&amp;rsquo;t predominantly people in the tech industry. Alex is a graduate student in physics at Stanford, so the party was full of PhD candidates and high school friends who&amp;rsquo;ve covered a spread across the different fields.</description></item><item><title>the gaps</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/the-gaps/</guid><description>thumping beats, reverberating ground a ritualized welcome or a dreadful threat to the entrants strangers and substances a perfect match for forgotten nights and regrettable fights the empty spaces of life those gaps in the space between the lived and the unlivable between the vocalized and the omitted water surges from within to fill those that make us ache with the rhythm of that fateful beat, that make us rage with the hot fury of those substances’ burn I reach out for the spaces yet they reach away an infinite chase, head after tail a still, pristine lake above a single drop triggers the climax below These gaps exist to be reached Yes, we live for reaching but oh!</description></item><item><title>uneven time</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/uneven-time/</guid><description>an art piece representing the fish of lijiang by James W Hedges
I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself catching myself from thinking too quickly recently, the thoughts tumbling over each other and jostling for the room to breathe. Sometimes my mind feels like a bumping nightclub in the rush of the night&amp;mdash;overwhelming sights and sounds fighting for your attention. The game is one of being more attractive, more provocative, more desirable than all the others, and the battleground is our senses.</description></item><item><title>commitment and obligation</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/commitment-and-obligation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/commitment-and-obligation/</guid><description>The first time I ran 3 miles was during a typical Houston summer, hot and humid. It was just past one, past the hottest time of day but still above 90, still hot enough to see the light shimmering in the liminal space between the planes where your eyes focused. I started cross country in middle school to follow my brother’s footsteps, and I kept with it because I figured it was a good way to keep myself fit.</description></item><item><title>Rituals at Scale: How we remixed templates</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rituals-remixing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>craft over career</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/craft-over-career/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter.
I came across this tweet today on a life philosophy to follow that really resonated with me.
mads mikkelsen, career coach https://t.co/WftIqaBxfd pic.twitter.com/OIAJZ6mtFm
&amp;mdash; E. Alex Jung (@e_alexjung) April 20, 2021 everything I do is the most important thing I do&amp;hellip;. I will be ambitious with my job and not my career.
The implication of this statement is that whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing now is the most important thing for you, not some stepping stone for a future greatness.</description></item><item><title>the mid-twenties</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/mid-twenties/</guid><description>This post was originally published on my newsletter. This was also my 1st installment in my 100 mini-essays experiment.
a colorful storefront I found in Buenos Aires (more at my instagram)
So I turned 24 yesterday and the biggest question on my mind (as it seems to have incepted all of my friends’ minds) is: does 24 count as “mid-twenties”? “Welcome to your mid-twenties” my friends quip.</description></item><item><title>Gambling on Dreams</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/gambling/</guid><description>A vibration ripples out from my phone. It’s a message from a classmate asking about my rooming plans for next semester with a not-so-subtle suggestion at a better option. I’m nearing the end of my first year in college, and having been successful at my quest to fit in, I’m tempted to change as little as possible to keep the good things going. The proposal to room with someone new (who I knew from the very intimate experience of recognizing their face across the dining hall every once in a while) was both an opportunity and a risk.</description></item><item><title>Dilution</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/dilution/</guid><description>Under my watchful eyes, a weight settles over the world. Thick layers of shadows pile on top of one another until all that’s left poking out in the sea of night are tiny fireflies, little torches signaling life. I look out my golden-ratioed window, a precise, technical masterpiece with a reinforced panel of glass acting as a projector for the production playing out beyond. In the distant horizon, the line where the sky meets the world and the galactic bend, glinting ever so inconspicuously, levels with my eyes.</description></item><item><title>Making the World a Better Place: A Valley of Smoke and Mirrors</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/better-world-delusion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/better-world-delusion/</guid><description>a beach along Route 1 covered by the fog (photo credit spencerchang.photography)
To communicate an identity requires some degree of self-delusion. A performer, in order to be convincing, must conceal “the discreditable facts that he has had to learn about the performance; in everyday terms, there will be things he knows, or has known, that he will not be able to tell himself.” ー Trick Mirror: Reflections on Self-Delusion by Jia Tolentino summarizing Erving Goffman In second grade, we did an assignment on our dream jobs.</description></item><item><title>Making the “Right” Decisions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</guid><description>A mother and cub flourishing in the remains of a whaling station in Grytviken&amp;ndash;an example of something &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; becoming wrong. (for more)
Growing up, I strove to do all the “right” things. I was told that doing well in school was good, so I studied, toiled, and recited for good grades. I was told that being polite and obedient was proper, so I sucked up my protests and did what was demanded of me without question.</description></item><item><title>George Floyd</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/george-floyd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/george-floyd/</guid><description>SF George Floyd Protest 06/03 for more see my instagram This week should have felt like another rude awakening for those of us who have rarely had to think about the problems in our criminal justice system and how our country handles protecting our communities.</description></item><item><title>Broken Lines</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</guid><description>a stack of logs on a Napa trip (for more photos)
But in a life of activity, one free from dramatic rupture, where the progress of things is unbroken by catastrophe, where the skin of our thoughts is regularly touched by new impressions, discoveries and influences, our maturation comes to follow a gradient that creates the illusion of a seamless line. With Uncle Hmad, the young man he was at the point of his arrest and the man he has become seemed to exist in parallel, destined never to meet and yet resonating against one another like two discordant musical notes.</description></item><item><title>a twinkle</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/a-twinkle/</guid><description>A shaft of moonlight pierces the curtain
In my concrete abode, a flare lighting the way out
The ephemeral promise draws me
like a firefly I seek my hopes.
The defeaning chorus of cicadas
consumes me in the darkness.
Out in the fields, the grains cultivated
What was promised eclipses the night
A permanent night light bathes me
as the swarm of stars engulfs me
from the infinite black canvas above</description></item><item><title>Crowdsourced Birthday Recommendations</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/crowdsourced-birthday-recs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/crowdsourced-birthday-recs/</guid><description>I collected anonymous (or not) birthday recommendations and feedback. It was amazing to hear from so many people, both close friends and acquaintances and their inner thoughts. I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful to everyone who filled it out!
It all started in a bright hospital room in downtown Houston&amp;hellip;
Ok maybe not that far back, but essentially I got the idea from my friend Kevin Lau who did the same thing for his birthday.</description></item><item><title>The War of Intentions and Beliefs</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</guid><description>What happens when good intentions are lost, everyone wants to be a hero, and the fight against evil spills over into innocents.</description></item><item><title>Decoding your Mind</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/decoding-your-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/decoding-your-mind/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Discovering a New Year</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/discovering/</guid><description>Exploration—the relinquishing of the old for something new and unknown. Why do we explore? What drives us to leave behind cozy homes, comfortable routines, and familiar lands, foods, and faces to seek out the new and unknown?</description></item><item><title>Opening the Lid on the Workspace Black Box</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/opening-the-lid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/opening-the-lid/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Rider</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rider/</guid><description>The night was cold and dark. The moon shone brightly, gently singing her graceful hymn. The light didn’t shine very far, however. A thick wall of sinister clouds prevented any escape of the beautiful song below.</description></item><item><title>Sublime Arts</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/sublime-arts/</guid><description>1:45 am. We had just gotten back from the movies, and I was going through the regular ritual of preparing for my nightly recharge. The room was pitch dark except for the flickering amalgam of multicolored lights dancing across the window: reflections mirroring the revelry of a city alive at night.
As I was finishing my movements in robotic silence, an irregular symphony of beats stirred me from my semi-wakeful, semi-listless state.</description></item><item><title>Rice Fields and Murky Identities</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rice-fields/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/rice-fields/</guid><description>Rice fields right outside 宜梧 (YiWu) Junior High School during sunset (taken on my Nikon D3400)
“来吃饭了！(literally, &amp;lsquo;come eat!&amp;rsquo; but interpreted as &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo;s ready!&amp;rsquo; )” rang through the hallways of my house, emanating from the kitchen. This was a daily occurrence, after a long day of school or work, signaling that dinner, which my 奶奶 (grandma) had lovingly prepared, was ready. Growing up in a Chinese American household, I was lucky to have my grandma live with us; this forced me to learn Mandarin from a young age because she couldn’t speak English.</description></item><item><title>From Student to Teacher</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/student-to-teacher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/student-to-teacher/</guid><description>Photo by Mwesigwa Joel on Unsplash
”誰是我們的老師啊？(Who are our teachers?)“
“是我們 (We are)” I blurted.
Shit. We had just finished a whole week of training where we were specifically told to pretend not to know Chinese to encourage our students to speak English. And I had just responded in Chinese to their question. Great, first minute of “teaching” and I already messed up. How am I gonna survive 2 weeks of this?</description></item><item><title>Stupid Scholars, the Power of Hands, and Free Lunches: Riding Through 4 Years of University</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/stupid-scholars/</guid><description>“It’ll be fine,” I reassured myself for what seemed like the millionth time. The mere prospect of a roller coaster ride had reduced me to a broken record. I’ve never been a follower of the camp that derives thrill, much less joy, from artificial fear. Horror movies are a hard no, especially at night, alone in my room, and maybe it’s obvious, but I had never ridden a roller coaster.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Knowledge Access and Retrieval at Airbnb</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/knowledge-graph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/knowledge-graph/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>