<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in data on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ephemeral permanence: an exploration of the future of digital data</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/ephemeral-permanence/</guid><description>I was talking to Sahil today about low pressure contexts, and we stumbled across an interesting point around how the ephemeral nature of things makes it feel low pressure and safe, but we also want to be able to leverage our technology for storing and retrieving data about every conversation we&amp;rsquo;ve had. How might we get the best of both: the safety of ephemeral thoughts and conversations and moments and the convenience of permanent records and written transcripts and preserved memories?</description></item><item><title>data stockholm syndrome</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/data-stockholm-syndrome/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year when holiday songs invade every gap of your awareness, overly ambitious resolutions are made, far too much home food is consumed, and, of course, you and your friends size each other up with your Spotify Wrapped. Our capitalist ideals have already dug themselves deep into the roots of our holiday traditions, in the compulsive gift giving and millions of click-bait Christmas gift listicles that collectively surface for a month and then fade away into the nethers of the Internet.</description></item></channel></rss>