<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ideas on Spencer Chang</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/ideas/</link><description>Recent content in ideas on Spencer Chang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.spencerchang.me/tags/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Everyday Magic</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/everyday-magic/</guid><description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t it mindboggling that we created machines that can fly and swim?
In October, I responded to Reboot&amp;rsquo;s manifesto, “Take Back the Future.”, which calls upon technologists to pursue and leverage their unique agency in shaping technology, which has an outsized impact on the future of our livelihoods, to advocate for the people who have less agency and push for a brighter, more equal future. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet from my response:</description></item><item><title>living to provoke</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/living-to-provoke/</guid><description>The other day, under the cover of dim lights embedded in elegant wooden fixtures, we took impassioned guesses at each other&amp;rsquo;s MBTI&amp;rsquo;s. Personality types are an interesting way we use to pretend to be in control of the world and knowing of the world&amp;rsquo;s secrets. We bucket each other into divisions of 16 and 9 and 25 and 12, assigning occupations and strengths, disposition and spirit animals. We tend to like hard divides because they give us the illusion of truth.</description></item><item><title>crazy ideas</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/crazy-ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/experiments/100posts/crazy-ideas/</guid><description>We had Coda&amp;rsquo;s Block Party today, which was a day-long event announcing a bunch of the huge features we&amp;rsquo;re launching soon and hosting many thought leaders to talk about their favorite &amp;ldquo;rituals,&amp;rdquo; repeated processes which keep you or your team productive and healthy. In the final fireside chat between Shishir, our CEO, and Reid Hoffman, a legend of venture investing, Shishir talked again about the initial meeting between them and how this idea seemed crazy at the time.</description></item><item><title>Making the “Right” Decisions</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/right-decisions/</guid><description>A mother and cub flourishing in the remains of a whaling station in Grytviken&amp;ndash;an example of something &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; becoming wrong. (for more)
Growing up, I strove to do all the “right” things. I was told that doing well in school was good, so I studied, toiled, and recited for good grades. I was told that being polite and obedient was proper, so I sucked up my protests and did what was demanded of me without question.</description></item><item><title>Broken Lines</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/broken-lines/</guid><description>a stack of logs on a Napa trip (for more photos)
But in a life of activity, one free from dramatic rupture, where the progress of things is unbroken by catastrophe, where the skin of our thoughts is regularly touched by new impressions, discoveries and influences, our maturation comes to follow a gradient that creates the illusion of a seamless line. With Uncle Hmad, the young man he was at the point of his arrest and the man he has become seemed to exist in parallel, destined never to meet and yet resonating against one another like two discordant musical notes.</description></item><item><title>The War of Intentions and Beliefs</title><link>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.spencerchang.me/posts/war-of-intentions/</guid><description>What happens when good intentions are lost, everyone wants to be a hero, and the fight against evil spills over into innocents.</description></item></channel></rss>